ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
电脑团
小酸奶!
翻译
吃冰棒
TL
翻译
时间轴
大葱ALX  念念  今
电脑狂人
第四季
第五集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
93年11月
至94年5月
我就是有点意外
Well, I was just a little bit surprised.
因为之前你困住了好久
Because, well, you know, you'd struggled for so long.
我得问一句
So I just -- I have to ask...
是谁写的新算法
Who wrote the new algorithm?
是我写的啊
I mean, I did.
但是还是多亏了博斯
Though I gotta give Bos credit.
他的想法很不错
He had a great idea.
我们把那叫做
Yeah, we're calling it the, uh,
"等候室"概念
the "waiting room" concept.
人们可以在现实生活中排队  在网上也能如此
People wait in line in life. Why not on the web?
所以我写了个排队程序
So I-I created a-a queuing program.
我们的网络爬虫很粗糙[粗鲁]
Yeah. Our crawler was rude.
我得好好调教它一下
I had to teach that sucker some manners.
那你好好玩
Well, uh, you enjoy the party.
不
No!
-天啊  -怎么了
- Oh, my God. - What is wrong?
真是太烦了
This is so annoying.
怎么了  是卡梅隆的游戏吗
What is that? Cameron's game?
我以为那个测评人是个混蛋  但是...
I thought that review guy was just an asshole, but...
这根本不可能
...this is actually impossible.
她好像根本就不想让人赢
Like, she doesn't want anyone to actually win.
你这三个都试过了吗
Well, did you try all three of these?
这三个都会让你回到起点
They all take you back to the beginning.
我去拿冰淇淋
I'm getting ice cream.
你觉得我会是个好间谍吗
Hey, you think I'd make a good spy?
我在前台留了号码
I leave message here on service,
但你怎么没打给我啊
but you do not call.
怎么  你想看点别的吗
Why? Do you want to watch something else?
不  其实我还挺喜欢的
No! I'm really into it.
-是吗  -她的口音太搞笑了
- Yeah? - Her accent is ridiculous.
你看了这个电影
How many times have you viewed
多少次了
this moving-picture show?
天啊  我不知道  太多次了  我都数不清了
Geez, I don't know. Too many times. I've lost count.
-在电影院看了四次  -天啊
- Four in the theater. - Oh, my God.
别这样  我喜欢的东西就很喜欢
Easy. I like what I like.
我喜欢你很喜欢你喜欢的东西
I like that you like what you like.
你最喜欢这种  完全可以理解
Totally makes sense that it's your favorite, though.
这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你开玩笑嘛
Are you kidding me?
这片子是讲一群吊儿郎当的家伙
It's a motley crew of dude friends pulling capers
只凭自己宅宅的技术和一股勇气
with nothing more than nerdy technical skills
搞出的一堆事端
and a dash of moxie.
"好运将会降临在你身边"
"Functioning superbly does come automatically to me."
运气
Fortunes!
你的是什么
What did you get?
什么  我看看
What? Let me see!
"你的有缘人即将到来"
"An exciting 'Tim' is coming my way."
该死
Damn it!
他肯定很喜欢摇摆舞
And I'll bet he likes swing dancing.
为什么会喜欢摇摆舞
Why swing dancing?
你不是每周五晚都会去吗
Yeah, isn't that the thing that you do every Friday night?
是轮滑
Roller derby.
真的吗
Seriously?
真不知道你怎么会把这两个东西搞混
I don't even know how you mix those two up.
那我得说  我脑子里想的全是
Well, in my defense, I was incredibly distracted
和你做爱
by how bad I wanted to sleep with you.
算你聪明
Nice save.
轮滑
Roller derby, huh?
真性感
That's hot.
我知道  你明天想来吗
I know. You want to come tomorrow?
好啊  好啊好啊
Yes. Yes, yes, I do.
等等
Wait.
明天轮到我看孩子
Yeah, I think I got the girls tomorrow.
好吧
Okay.
我也不知道
Well, I don't know.
要不
Maybe...
要不我问问她们想不想跟来
Maybe I'll see if they want to come, too.
好
Okay.
那好
Okay then.
我能不能倒回去一点
Do you mind if we rewind a bit?
我可不想错过一点刺激冒险
I don't want to miss any madcap adventures.
我们可不止错过一点了
Oh, I think we've missed way more than a bit.
我在前台留了号码
I leave message here on service,
但你怎么没打给我啊
but you do not call.
再看一遍
One more time.
我在前台留了号码  但你怎么没打给我啊
I leave message here on service, but you do not call.
然后那个人大老远地赶来我的住处
And then the guy drove all the way back to my house
把我忘拿了的包送过来
to bring me the bag that I forgot
因为他说他知道我舍不得我最爱喝的饮料
'cause he said he knew I loved my Yoo-hoo.
你能相信吗
Can you believe that?
他们简直是我遇见过的最好心的人了
I mean, these people are the nicest people on the planet.
住在城里还有什么好处啊
I don't know why anyone lives in the city anymore.
比如你不用开半小时车去超市买吃喝
So you don't have to drive 30 minutes to get your groceries.
-是吧  -说得对
- I mean... - Good point.
我们也并不是全错
We weren't totally wrong, though.
什么
What?
彗星
Comet.
搜索市场本来就是抢滩圈地
Search was always a land grab.
可我本以为我们占领了高地
But I thought we planted a flag.
结果有了这么一大笔钱
Now, flush with all that cash,
流浪者的进化速度我们根本不能比
Rover will be able to innovate in ways that we cannot,
尤其是凭目前的构架
especially with the current structure.
所以我
So I...
我想说的是
What I guess I'm trying to say is...
你说得对
you were right.
算法搜索就是未来方向
Algorithmic search is the future--
该死
Shit.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我不知道我们为什么没有及时调整
I don't know why we would wait to pivot.
今晚我要在清风房车过夜
I think I'm gonna stay at the Airstream tonight.
什么
What?
等你到了都11点了
It'll be 11:00 by the time you get there.
那好吧  想去就去  不过
All right, yeah. Do what you want, but...
-怎么了  -我只是
- What? - I-I was really hoping
非常希望你明早能和我一起去彗星
you'd come in to Comet with me in the morning.
我希望能和戈登组织一次头脑风暴
I want to have a-a brainstorming session with Gordon,
你的见解会非常有帮助
and we could really use your perspective.
乔  我不是故意和你提起
Joe, I didn't mean to get in your head
-什么算法的事的  好吗  -你
- about the algorithm thing, okay? - You --
-别纠结了  -不是你提的  是流浪者
- Forget it. - You didn't. Rover did.
你们现在做的就挺好的
You should just keep doing what you were doing.
你们的方法非常  特别
You have a very... unique approach.
就一天  要不两天
One day, maybe two.
不  我现在不想掺和到
No. I don't want to get in the middle of things
你和戈登之间
with you and Gordon right now.
我不是让你来调解
I'm not asking you to mediate.
我是说我们公私分明非常重要
I'm telling you it's important that we keep things separate.
卡梅  流浪者就要碾压我们了
Cam, Rover is gonna kick our ass.
又不能怨我
That's not my fault!
我也没说怨你  我
I didn't say it was your fault. I'm --
我在向你求助
I'm asking for your help.
是啊  现在才说
Yeah, now.
我都说你是对的了
I said that you were right.
好吧  你和戈登之前不希望我
Okay, you and Gordon didn't want me
加入你们的小团体
to be a part of your little club.
你当时都不肯听我说话
You weren't even listening to me.
不是的
That is not true.
我问过你是否想参与
I asked you if you wanted to be involved,
而你拒绝了我
and you turned me down.
我还问过你是否想搬进来
I also asked if you wanted to move in,
你也不想
and you don't want to do that, either.
我经常邀你去房车
I ask you out to the Airstream all the time.
我在那里面都直不起腰
I can't stand up in the damn thing!
我已经很迁就你
Look, I've been really understanding with you,
非常耐心了
beyond patient.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没意识到我们还在算计这个
I didn't realize we were running a tab.
凯蒂快输给我了
I got Katie on the ropes.
我在放水让他赢
I'm letting him win.
别胡扯  看我手劲
Oh, please. Get a load of this wrist! Aah!
不
No!
看招
Look at that one!
戈登
Gordon!
怎么了
What?
我都听不到自己思考了
I can't hear myself think.
是你想买这个的  你自己选地方摆的
You wanted the thing. You picked the place for it.
今天可是周五
Look. It's Friday, okay?
只有两队人没有做完
All but two teams have clear queues.
休息一下  别想了
Maybe take a break from thinking.
现在我输入"达拉斯牛仔队"
So now when I put in "Dallas Cowboys,"
排在最前的搜索结果是最热门的粉丝网站
the first results are the top fan sites.
好吧  他们做了改进  这是不可避免的
Okay, so they've improved. That was inevitable.
麻烦的是接下来的几个结果
It's the next few results where we're in trouble.
奇泽姆牛车道历史协会
The Chisholm Trail Historic Society.
德州牛仔巡回赛的排名
The rankings for the Texas rodeo circuit,
以及特哈诺乡村混合风
and, of course, the country-Tejano
经典曲目  《怜悯我》
crossover classic, "Mercy Me,"
演唱者  达拉斯牛仔
by our friends the Dallas Cowboys.
我不明白
I don't get it.
我们上次看这个时
I mean, the last time we looked at it,
这还是缺点
that was a bad thing.
那时它们排得太靠前
Then they rank too high.
他们成功让搜索结果
They've managed to make the results
对于一般用户来说足够准确
accurate for the average user
同时还能考虑到非主流人群
while still accounting for the outlier.
非常厉害
It's brilliant.
如果结果这么厉害  那么
Well, if the results are that impressive, then --
就是这么厉害
They are!
我们需要扩建编程团队
We need to build out our coding team,
雇佣分析员  统计学家
hire analysts, statisticians.
听着
Look.
这个可就有得谈了
This is a much larger conversation.
那我们就谈
So let's have it.
可今天是周五
It-- It's Friday.
大多数人都有空
And most of the queues are clear.
好吧
Okay.
增长已经变缓
Growth has slowed.
但我们仍在增长
Yet we're still growing.
这样下去的话长久不了
Not for long with this.
不  我觉得你夸大其词了
No, I think you're overstating things.
我理解你的顾虑
Look, I get it
你是担心我们付不起这个钱
if you don't think we're gonna be able to pay for it.
我觉得你第一次就做对了
I think you were right the first time.
我们现有的可行
What we have is working.
彗星很棒
Comet is great.
你能放松一点吗
Okay? Will you please just relax?
行吗
Okay?
凯蒂就玩桌上冰球  还拿挺高的工资
We sure are paying Katie a hell of a lot to play air hockey.
好吧
Okay.
你究竟想干什么
What's this really about?
-保障这家公司的未来  -是吗
- Ensuring the future of this company. - Yeah?
因为在我看来  一切如常
Because from where I stand, everything seems fine.
而你  今早一进来
You, on the other hand, walked in here this morning
就像有人往你的燕麦粥里拉了屎一样
like somebody took a dump in your oatmeal.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
在我看来
From where I stand,
你似乎对这家公司的情况毫不在意
it looks like you don't care what happens to this company
只要你能继续上首席本体论专家
as long as you get to keep screwing the chief ontologist!
要不你去透透气吧
Why don't you get some air?
首轮招聘将在工程部进行
First wave of hires will be in the engineering department.
预计本月底前招到四名程序员
Four programmers by the end of the month,
一名产品管理总监
a director of product management,
第二季度内招到一支测试小组
and a Q.A. team by Q2.
你昨晚还尽兴吗
You have fun last night?
当然  当然  很开心
Sure. Sure, nice do.
是啊  我特别兴奋
Yeah, I was so wired.
我大半夜没睡着  看那个算法
I stayed up half the night, looking at that algorithm.
太了不起了  你不觉得吗
It's just so impressive, don't you think?
西塞尔真的做到了
Cecil really came through.
第一张表单上写了
On the top sheet,
我们要将首席财务官这个职位外包出去...
you'll see we're outsourcing the CFO role --
他仅用一次完美的更新
I mean, he solved every problem
就解决了困扰了他好几个月的难题
he's been wrestling with for months in one elegant update.
我想他可能是终于找到了灵感
Well, I guess the muse finally had something to say.
你不奇怪是什么卡了他这么久吗
Don't you wonder what took him so long?
并不
I don't.
我们稍后再谈编程部扩招
Let's put a pin in expanding the programming department for now.
西塞尔在重压下表现得如此可圈可点
Cecil performed so well under pressure,
我们就看看他能不能再次给我们惊喜
let's, uh, let's see if he surprises us again.
这听起来会有点怪  但是...
This is gonna sound a little weird, but...
有首歌一直在我脑中挥之不去
I got this song stuck in my head,
但我想不起来是什么歌了...
and I can't get it out, and --
很喜欢玩这个
Love this game.
-好吧  -开始吧
- Okay. - Go for it.
《夺宝奇兵》
"Indiana Jones."
肯定不是
Definitely not.
再来
Go again.
《笑是如此费力  而哭只用坐上一辆火车》
"It Takes a Lot to Laugh, It Takes a Train to Cry."
鲍勃·迪伦创作并演唱
这不是一首歌吧
That can't be a song.
是有缘人的最爱
It's exciting Tim's favorite.
我不知道
I don't know.
或许是我编的歌
Maybe I made it up.
你一定能想起来的
I bet it will come to you.
是吗
Yeah?
当你最不抱期望的时候
When you least expect it.
真的吗
Oh, yeah?
我不想小题大做
I don't want to make it more of a thing,
但今天乔...
but Joe today --
是啊  听我说...
Yeah, listen...
这真的没有借口
There's really no excuse,
但有时候  乔就会...
but sometimes, Joe just can get --
海莉为此很尴尬
It just got awkward with Haley,
也许你该和她谈谈
and maybe you should talk to her.
怎么了  她说什么了吗
What? Did she say something?
没有
No.
她肯定听到乔的话了  所以
I'm sure she heard him, so...
她知道我们在约会
Well, she knows we're dating, you know?
对  约会是知道
Yeah. Dating.
你是想让我和我14岁的女儿
You want me to have a conversation
聊我的性生活吗
with my 14-year-old daughter about my sex life?
不是  我也说不好啦
No. No. I don't know.
-怎么了  -也许吧
- What? - Maybe!
她现在跟我怪怪的
She just got weird with me.
听着
Okay, listen.
如果海莉的态度你都接受不了的话
If you can't handle a little weirdness with Haley,
那你肯定过不了琼妮那关
there's no way you're surviving trial by Joanie.
好吧
Fair enough.
我会做好心理准备的
Okay. I'll pack extra padding.
天呐
Oh, geez!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
我能进去吗
Can I come in?
当然
Sure.
喝咖啡吗
Coffee?
-好的  -好
- Sure. - Yeah.
你没回我的邮件
You haven't responded to my e-mails.
不是
No.
我就是有一阵没查邮件了
I just haven't checked in a while.
抱歉  经过雅达利那事之后
Sorry. After everything with Atari, I just...
当然  那事我很遗憾
Oh, yeah. I'm -- I'm sorry to hear about that.
我知道你很努力
No, I know you worked hard.
等等  你该不会大老远来这儿
Oh, wait. You didn't come all the way out here
只是因为担心我吧
'cause you were worried about me, did you?
我要和几个开发人员见面
I had meetings with a few developers.
那好
Cool.
一石多跨大洲鸟
Many birds, one transcontinental stone.
那你确实是来打我的
So you are here to kill me.
我需要你签个字
I just need you to sign these.
好
Sure.
你就不能寄过来吗
You couldn't mail them?
我寄了
I did.
和你的日记还有毛衣一起寄过来的
They were in the box with your journals and the sweater.
好吧
Okay.
等等  你没收到吗
Wait. Did you not get them?
不  收到了
No, I did.
但是箱子被卡车撞了
Uh, it got hit by a truck.
好吧  卡梅
Okay, Cam.
真的  我知道听起来
No, I-I know it sounds...
我
I...
你就告诉我签哪儿吧
I'll just sign whatever you want.
这太不可理喻了
This is insane.
说真的  她这是疯了
Seriously, she has lost her mind!
各位好
Hey, guys.
我有几分钟时间  就想过来看看
Just had a few minutes and thought I'd check in.
博斯和谭雅跟你们说了我的想法吗
Have Bos and Tanya walked you through my thinking?
我们正在说呢
Uh, yeah, we're working through that right now.
恕我直言  我们觉得应该
With respect, we would prefer
先雇用编程人员
to prioritize programming hires.
我能理解这种想法
Yeah, I understand the instinct.
在大多数情况下  我也同意  但是
And in most circumstances, I would agree. But --
没有员工的前提下先找业务发展主管
It makes no sense to bring in a head of business development
这根本不合理
when we don't have a staff!
我们只是在讨论  兄弟
Hey, we're just talking here, dude.
我们很感激你的领导  唐娜
We're all grateful for your leadership, Donna,
但我觉得我们已经完全证明了自己
but I think that we have more than proven ourselves.
我会很感激
And I would appreciate it --
我们都会感激能让我们
Well, we would all appreciate the respect
在没有那么多干涉的情况下
of being able to run our own company
经营我们自己的公司
without this much interference.
你是一位极其出色的程序员
You are an excellent programmer.
谢谢
Thanks.
考虑到过去的几个月里
And considering all you've accomplished
你所达成的成就
in the last couple months,
我不觉得招募新的工程师
I don't see a big value add
能带来很大的价值
in additional engineers.
我懂
Yeah, I-I get that.
但是
but, you know, I mean,
想想如果我不需要再操心
think of -- think of what I could accomplish
细枝末节或是数据库
if I didn't have to worry about the cosmetic stuff
我又能成就多少
or the database.
那些很让人分心
It's just distracting.
而如果我能专注于
And if I could just focus on --
功能性的开发
on developing functionality,
那将有无限可能
you know, who knows what's possible?
所以你并不需要程序员  你只需要打杂的
So you don't need programmers. You just need coding grunts?
都要  两种都要
Uh, well, both. We need both.
那么
Well...
我会满足你的需求
I want you to have what you need.
-谢谢你  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thanks.
你不会后悔的
You won't regret it.
但网页搜索的概念并非我们专有
But the idea of search isn't proprietary,
而我们的流程却是的
and our process, however, is.
所以在我引进新的人才之前
So before we bring in any outside talent,
你还是先和我们的法律团队一起
why don't we get you with our legal team
申请所有必要的专利吧
and file all the necessary patents?
我们拿到种子基金的时候已经申过了
We did that back when we got seed.
那个专利是针对医疗记录索引的
That patent was for a medical records indexing method.
你觉得那能囊括西塞尔最近的创新吗
Do you believe that covers Cecil's recent innovations?
律师团会需要详细的技术参数
The lawyers are gonna want detailed specifications --
算法的原理和功能  书面的
how it works, what it does -- in writing.
你不觉得我们有点过于谨慎了吗
And I -- Don't you think we're being overly cautious here?
不  我觉得我们谨慎得刚刚好
No, I think I'm being the exact right amount of cautious.
这应该不是问题吧
I assume that's not gonna be a problem.
不  完全不是
No. No problem at all.
一旦我们搞定知识产权
Once we lock down the I.P.,
你们想要多少工程师就能招多少
you can have all the engineers you want.
我跟你说  她知道了
I'm telling you, she knows.
她在怀疑  但她什么都无法证明
She's got her suspicions. She can't prove anything.
谁管她能不能证明
Who cares if she can prove it?
她可以让我的生活一团糟  她已经做到了
She can make my life miserable. She already is.
你得给我镇定下来  好吗
You've gotta get it the hell together, all right?
和律师团谈  告诉他们整个机理
Get with the lawyers, walk them through how this thing works,
然后继续下一阶段
and then move on.
我知道唐娜也会的
I know Donna will, too.
你根本没听进去我的话  我做不到
You're not hearing me. I can't.
那里面有我写的程序块
All right, there are these chunks of what I wrote in there,
我只知道它们之间是怎么关联的
but the way it's connected, I-I get what's happening,
但我无法解释为什么
but I can't explain it.
写这些程序的人高我一个层次  老兄
Whoever wrote this is on another level, man.
-别贬低你自己  -你去问那人要具体参数吧
- No, don't sell yourself short. - Go ask him for the damn specs.
你知道怎么做这些...
You know how to do all--
我有点沮丧我们无从知道
You know, I'm kind of bummed we're never gonna find out
那到底是什么声音
what that sound was.
我没跟你说啊
I never told you.
没  是什么
No. What?
你绝不会相信的
You're not gonna believe it.
-是个老妇人被捆在了床上  -接近了
- It's an old woman tied to a bed. - Close.
是只椅子上的鹦鹉
It's a parrot on a chair.
-什么  -老大了
- What? - A huge one.
可能是只金刚鹦鹉
A macaw, maybe.
不  那是人类尖叫的声音
No. The screams were human.
是啊
I know.
等等  你怎么进去的
Wait. How did you get in?
真辅的公寓漏水
There was a leak in Shinsuke's apartment,
敏明只得为水管工打开了他们家的门
so Toshiaki had to open the place up for a plumber,
我知道那是我唯一的机会了
and I just knew that that was my only chance.
那刮蹭声呢
What -- What about the scraping?
是椅子
It's a chair.
什么
What?
是椅子
It's the chair.
就是那种金属椅子
One of those metal ones with the --
后面刻着心
with the heart on the back.
鸟能把椅子从一扇窗
The bird would drag the chair...
拖到另一扇那里
from one window to another.
起初  我没搞懂是为什么
And at first, I couldn't figure out why,
直到我看到巷子里有只猫
until I saw that there's a cat in the alley.
他们在玩跨种族的
So they had this intraspecies
躲猫猫游戏
game of peek-a-boo going on.
太奇怪了
It's so bizarre.
-是一只鸟  -嗯
- So a bird... - Yeah.
用喙  拖着那把椅子
...drags the chair... with its beak?
老大一只鸟了
It's a big bird.
不会的  我不信
No, I don't believe you.
我为什么要撒谎呢
Well, why would I lie about that?
你要搬去哪
Where are you moving?
我们在世田谷区找了栋房子
We got a place in Setagaya-ku.
在郊区吗
The suburbs?
没想到啊
That is...unexpected.
我们要生孩子了
We're having a baby.
我替你高兴
I'm happy for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了
All right.
你看上去挺好的
You seem good.
我是挺好
I am.
对不起
I'm sorry.
一切都很对不起
For all of it.
嗯
Yeah.
再见
Itterasshai!
我要回家了  但我去溜冰场能顺道送你
I'm heading home, but you're on my way to the rink,
如果你想...
so if you want me to --
你没事吧
Feeling all right?
嗯  没什么可写的
Yeah. Nothing to report.
7点你家见
7:00 at your spot?
好啊
You got it.
戈登·克拉克
Gordon Clark.
他在吗  他不接电话
Is he around? He's not picking up.
嗯  我去找找他
Yeah. Let me see if I can get him.
好
Okay.
卡梅打来了
Cam's on the line.
我都不知道我是在解决什么问题
I don't even know what problem I'm trying to solve.
我不知道他在哪  我回头让他打给你吧
Look, I don't know where he is. Can I have him call you?
好  再见
Okay. Bye.
或许我们加个搜索栏
Maybe we add a search bar.
不像流浪者的爬虫那样  但我们让用户可以
Not with a crawler like Rover, but we give users the option
在我们的索引内搜索
to search our own index.
好
Okay.
这我可以同意
I mean, I could get behind that.
是吗  我也不清楚
Yeah? I don't know.
怎么了  伙计
What's going on, man?
我在那下面
I was just down there,
在一堆便贴里待了三年
surrounded by Post-it notes for three years,
我刚觉得自己已经掌握了大局
and just when I feel like I've got my arms around it...
却又看不到了
I can't see it anymore.
我们又是在谈未来的事了
So we're talking about the future again.
我该给她打回去
I should call her back.
这是你十年前所预见的吗
Is this what you saw 10 years ago?
因为当年你跑来我车库时
Because it's not what I saw for myself
我可没想象到会是这样
when you showed up in my garage.
问题就在这里
That's the point.
重点从来都不是结果
It was never about where it ended up.
而是感觉
It was... about how it felt.
我看得到未来时
When I saw it...
我知道跟你建立样东西会是什么感觉
I knew how it would feel to build something with you.
但这...
But this --
周五下午  一片清净
Friday afternoon, all the queues are clear --
我不知道接下来会怎么样
I don't know what comes next.
我们大部分人类
Most of us in the human race,
我们都无从得知接下来会如何
we don't get to know what's next.
我们只能随机应变
I mean, we just feel shit as it's thrown at us.
我们只有此时此刻
This right now is all there is.
欢迎来到未来  乔·麦克米伦
Welcome to the future, Joe MacMillan.
我不敢说别人  但是
I mean, I can't speak for anyone else, but...
我是很高兴有你在的
I'm sure glad to have you here.
之前的事很抱歉
I'm really sorry about earlier.
没事的
Don't worry about it.
但如果你再在我孩子面前
But if you ever scream about my sex life
为我私生活的事吼我
in front of my kid again...
我会扯下你的脑袋  冲你喉咙里拉屎
I will rip off your head and shit down your throat.
搜索栏是个好点子
Search bar is a good idea.
我们该做那个
We should do that.
你好啊
Hey, there!
我不是有意这么突然闯过来
Well, I don't mean to barge in on you like this.
我找你一天了
I been trying you all day.
所以就来碰碰运气
Thought I'd take a flyer.
我正好有事呢
You know what, I'm just in the middle of something.
我们可以回头说吗
Do you mind if we talk later?
这事要不了多久
No, this won't take but a sec.
乔在吗
Is Joe around?
不  他正要回家
No. He's uh, on his way home.
-你要找他吗  -不
- Do you need to talk to him? - No.
就找你  亲爱的
Just you, darling.
听着
Look.
我知道我们怎么说的
I know what we said,
要是还有别的办法
and I wouldn't ask,
-我也不会求你  卡梅  -不行
- Cam, if there's any other way. - No!
-我也没办法  -不行
- I wouldn't ask. - No.
不行  博斯  我们说好不再加补丁  更新
No. Bos, we said no patches, no updates.
那一次就完了
It was a one-time deal.
不  没那么麻烦
No, it's nothing that grand.
我就是需要技术参数  好申请专利
I just need a little help with the tech specs for the patent.
什么  你是说  他做了一半工作
What? You're telling me he wrote half the work,
还没法解释清楚吗
and he can't explain it to you?
他需要点指导
Well, he could use some guidance, huh?
就跟他通会儿电话
Just a few minutes on the phone.
天呐  不行
Jesus. No!
你答应过这事不会再找回到我身上来
You promised me that this would never come back to me.
是不会的
No, and it won't.
不会的  西塞尔没理由说出去
It won't. Cecil got no reason to spill.
天呐  这太蠢了
Oh, God. This is so stupid.
你为什么不能跟她直说
Why can't you just talk to her?
好吧
Sure, sure.
只要你肯告诉乔
Soon as you tell Joe.
你真希望他
You really want him --
你希望他都知道吗
You want him to know about all this?
听着  卡梅
Look, Cam.
你走吧
Okay, you need to leave.
卡梅
Cam.
这对我们都有好处
This is gonna help the both of us.
不  这是个错误
No, this was a mistake.
我们再也不要谈起这事了
We don't talk about this again.
卡梅  求你
Cam, please.
卡梅
Cam?
Cam!
卡梅  求你
Cam, please.
我本该放过他的
I should have let it slide,
但都十年了  我一直假装没看到他会
but after a decade of pretending to not notice him kick the ball
把高尔夫当足球一样踢
back on the fairway like it was soccer...
我要么得说点什么
I was either gonna have to say something
要么就要开小车撞他了
or run him over with a cart.
天呐  他一定气坏了
Oh, God, he must have been furious.
他没表露出来
He covered well.
他又打了两个洞  才找了个借口
It took him two more holes before he found an excuse
放弃不打了
to wrap his nine iron a tree.
我也是个好胜的人
You know, I'm as competitive as they come,
但我无法想象一个人怎么会那么大胆地作弊
but I can't imagine what compels a person to cheat so brazenly.
那是一生都被人告知获胜是你的天赋权利
A long life of being told that winning is your birthright.
约翰说得好
John had a good line.
你怎么说得来着  约翰
What was that? John.
-什么  -关于伊莱亚斯
- What? - About Elias.
他就是只小龙虾
Yeah, man's just a little lobster,
当自己是小龙虾之王了
convinced he's king of the crawdads.
真逗
Funny.
你去买单吧
Why don't you get the check?
我还是无法相信
I still can't believe it.
她也该停止放水让那白痴赢了
Well, yeah, it's about time she stopped letting that yahoo win.
她让杆让得太狠了
It was killing her handicap.
不  你明白我的意思
No, you know what I'm talking about.
我们今晚就别聊这个了  唐娜
Let's take the night off, Donna.
真是奇迹啊
I mean, it's miraculous, really.
那孩子又不是能走在水上
The kid can't walk on water.
我想到个点子  让他改变了思路
I had an idea. It shifted his thinking.
仅此而已
That's all.
只是这点子也太厉害了
Just must have been one hell of an idea.
还是你想的
And coming from you,
你这样的技术专家
a tech expert such as yourself, no less.
这又不需要专业知识
Well, it didn't take no expertise.
我不过是想到现实生活中也会排队等候
I just figured you wait in line in real life,
不如也在网上等
might as well wait in line on the Internet.
西塞尔意识到
Cecil realized--
我们的网络爬虫太粗糙[粗鲁]
Our crawler was rude.
是啊  我们得调教调教它们
Yeah, we had to teach it some manners.
得调教调教它们
Had to teach it some manners?
你真会鬼扯
You are so full of shit.
你喝多了吧
How many of those have you had?
我在这城里到处是敌人
I have enemies all over this town,
你居然带来外人捣鼓我的项目
and you bring someone in to poke around my project.
你说什么呢
What did -- What the hell are you talking about?
你就没想过
Did it not even occur to you
或许有人会想伤害我吗
that maybe someone out there is trying to hurt me?
-看来你是心里有愧  -得了
- Sounds like you're nursing a guilty conscience. - Oh, please!
别把矛头调过来对着我
Don't go trying to turn this around on me.
你根本没理由认为
I think there's a reason why
-我是想坑你  -你太鲁莽了
- you think I'm trying to screw you... - You were being reckless!
你现在就这样
...is that's all you know how to do.
天呐  我都不认识你了  唐娜
God damn it, I don't even know who you are anymore, Donna!
我是本来会开了你的人
I'm the woman who would have fired your ass
只不过是顾忌黛安
if you didn't have Diane's skirt to hide behind.
你这些年还不是仰仗她的照顾
Well, shit, you've been hiding behind her skirt for years.
-多少年了  -我帮了你个忙
- Years! - I did you a favor.
我当初之所以让你加入
The only reason I brought you on in the first place
就是因为她担心你无聊
was because she was worried you were bored!
博斯  博斯
Bos? Bos?
约翰  约翰
John! John!
约翰
John!
叫救护车
Get some help!
约翰  天呐  约翰
John! Oh, my God. John!
看着我  约翰  撑住
Look at me! John, stay with me.
博斯沃思太太
Mrs. Bosworth?
其实我...算了
Actually, I... Never mind.
他不会有事的
He's gonna be okay.
好吗  跟我来
All right? Come with me.
他怎么样了
How is he?
他...稳定了
Oh, he's -- he's stable.
好吧
Okay.
他们要做...
They were doing a...
我忘记叫什么了
I forget what it's called.
就是检查堵塞
It's to check for blockages.
黛安正跟医生在一起  肯定会知道更多情况
Diane's with the doctor now. I'm sure there's more news.
罗伯茨医生  四号线
Dr. Roberts, line four.
Dr. Roberts, pick up four.
怎么回事
What happened?
我也不清楚
I'm -- I'm not sure.
我们在一起吃饭  他本来好好的
We were at dinner, and he was fine.
突然就...不好了
And...then he wasn't.
我们今天吵了一架
We had a fight today.
我很过分
I was mean.
你不能责怪自己
Well, you -- you can't blame yourself.
你们吵什么了
What was the fight about?
是你啊
So it was you.
他不会有事的
He's gonna be all right.
他是个坚强的家伙
He's a tough son of a bitch.
黛安跟医生在一起呢
Diane's with the doctors now.
她在了解情况
She's getting an update.
你没事吧
You okay?
我不知道你在干什么
I don't know what you're doing,
但别插手我的生意  和我的生活
but stay out of my business, and stay out of my life.
-天呐  我超爱她  -是吧
- Oh, my God. I love her! - Right?!
天啊
Oh, God!
她好酷
She's so bad!
你想听吗
You want to listen?
不了  谢谢
No. No, I'm fine.
丫头  你没事吧
Yo, punk, you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
博斯不会有事的
Bos is gonna be all right.
我就是累了
I'm just tired.
我能借走这个吗
Can I borrow this?
当然
Sure.
海莉
Haley.
你要走吗
You headed out?
你在听什么
What you listening to?
没什么
Oh, nothing.
流行乐吗
Show tunes?
是啊  《皮平》
Yeah. "Pippin."
别逗了
Really, though.
压力会使我的症状恶化
Stress exacerbates my symptoms, so, um...
这能让我冷静下来
this calms me down.
那是恩雅咯
Enya, then.
不是
No.
是
It's uh...
是我
It's me.
我录下了自己说话
I recorded myself just talking,
提醒自己事情没那么糟
reminding myself that things aren't so bad.
那很美
That's beautiful.
我们都该那么做
We should all do that.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
说吧
Yeah, no, absolutely.
你的日记有规律吗
Is there a pattern in your journals?
几年前
You know, a few years back,
我对此很着迷
I-I got, you know, really nuts about it,
每周末都会把一切
and I put everything into a spreadsheet
制成电子表
at the end of each week.
然后我找朋友  盖博  建了个
Then I had my friend, Gabe -- he built out
数据分析程序
this statistical analysis program
能绘制图表  报告
that would spit out charts and graphs and reports and...
但是
But...
抱歉  很抱歉
Look, I'm really sorry
我今晚错过了轮滑
I missed roller derby this evening.
没事  下周还有的
Don't be. It'll be there next week.
能跟琼妮好好玩玩感觉很棒
It was nice to get some good time in with Joanie.
她很有趣
She's fun.
她真的很喜欢你  这可不简单
She really likes you, which is...something.
今晚谢谢你
Thanks for tonight.
我真的很感激
You know, I really appreciate it.
还早呢  我们可以看电影
It's still early. We can...watch a movie.
我真的好累
I'm really tired.
好吧
Okay.
-没事吧  -嗯
- Is that okay? - Yeah.
真的吗
You sure?
当然  明天找我
Yeah. Call me tomorrow?
嗯
Yeah.
当然
Yeah, no, of course. I'll --
我一早就找你
I'll call you first thing in the morning.
停车
Pull over.
怎么了
What's wrong?
你能不能停车
Can you just pull over?
求你
Please.
我今天见过汤姆
I saw Tom today.
他来这儿工作
He had some work here,
我得签些文件
and, uh, I had to sign something.
无所谓了
It doesn't matter.
但我开始想
But I started thinking...
我当时为什么最终把
about why I finally told him...
你我的事告诉了他
about you and me.
因为当时  我想着
'Cause at the time, I thought
只有那样才能挽救我们
that it was the only way to save us.
但现在
But now...
我觉得我是希望他离开我
I think I wanted him to leave.
是我写了那个算法
I wrote the algorithm.
我是为了博斯  为了帮他
I did it for Bos -- to help him.
他的储蓄都赔了
He lost all his money and
他还没告诉黛安
he hasn't told Diane,
事情很严重
and it's a big mess.
我心里一部分
A part of me just...
只想看看我是不是能做到
wanted to see if I could do it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你为什么告诉我
Why are you telling me this?
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
好吧  继续走
Okay, keep coming.
天呐  我在开车
Oh, God. I'm driving. I'm driving.
海莉落下了她的生物书
Haley left her bio book.
她周末要用吗
Does she need it for the weekend?
你好
Hello.
你知道吗
Do you know?
我不知道  但我能让她早上再打给你吗
I don't, but can I have her call you in the morning?
好啊
Sure.
那个
It's, um --
彗星  对她很有好处
It's been good for her. Comet.
是啊
Yeah.
她真的长大了
She's really growing into her skin.
是啊  我也很欣慰
Yeah. I'm glad you see it, too.
她...
She's, um...
她在那里就是另外一个人
God, she's just such a different person there.
也不能那么说  她就是更...
Or not different. She's just more --
我懂的
Yeah, I know what you mean.
我...
Look, um...
我知道流浪者的事搞得很复杂  但是...
I know it's been complicated with Rover, but --
唐娜  没事的
Look. Donna, it's fine.
今晚  很让人难受
Tonight was...hard.
是啊
Yeah.
我无法想象
I can't imagine.
天呐  黛安看到他时那声音
God, the sound of Diane's voice when she saw him, it was...
我和他才吵了架
And he and I had been arguing.
我对他很过分
I was really rough on him.
别  别那样
Don't. Don't.
不  是真的  我...
No, really, I...
我说了很过分的话
I said some awful things.
唐娜  那不怪你
Donna, it's not your fault.
你不在场  你不知道
You weren't there. You don't know.
是啊  他欠了30万呢
Yeah, well, he owes 300 grand.
他赔了一大笔钱
Sunk a bunch of money into a bad deal
不敢告诉黛安
and didn't tell Diane.
他估计是因为这个才去你那儿工作的
It's probably the real reason he went to work for you.
他起初来找我借
You know, he came to me first asking to borrow it,
我拒绝了他
and I turned him down,
所以如果要怪谁
so, if you're assigning blame to anyone...
唐娜
Donna.
你不会有事吧
You gonna be okay?
当然
Sure.
嗯
Yes.
晚安  戈登
Night, Gordon.
晚安
Good night.
BGM: Rid of Me  By  PJ Harvey